vpweb.co.uk 2009-06-28

# Vistaprint Privacy & Security

Privacy PolicyBack To TopVistaprint recognises the importance of maintaining your privacy. We value your privacy and appreciate your trust in us. This Privacy Policy applies to current and former visitors to our website and to our online customers. By visiting and/or using our website, you agree to this Privacy Policy.This Privacy Policy explains the information practices that apply to personally identifiable information that we collect about you as an individual when you visit and/or use our website. Any information that we collect about you while you are visiting or using our website will be handled in accordance with this Vistaprint Privacy Policy and will not be shared except in accordance with this Vistaprint Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy does **_not_** apply to information about you collected by our affiliates or third party websites that may post links or advertisements on or otherwise be accessible from the Vistaprint website. The information collected by these affiliates or third party websites is subject to their own privacy policies.Information We Collect:This section of our Privacy Policy describes the categories of information collected by Vistaprint. All data that we collect is processed and stored in Devonshire, Bermuda. You have the option not to provide information, however, withholding information may prevent you from being able to use some of our website features. _Information Collected Automatically:_ Whenever you visit our website, we automatically collect some information about your transactions with us, and your use of our website. For example, we automatically collect your IP address, for Vistaprint internal use only, such as to help us diagnose problems with our server and administer our website. We also automatically track certain information about your activities on our website such as the type of web browser you are using and click stream data. If you are a registered Vistaprint customer, we link this automatically-collected data to the personally identifiable information we collect about you described below. We use this information to do internal research on your interests and to help us better understand and serve you. _Information You Send To Us:_ If you choose to provide us with personal information, such as by sending us an e-mail or by filling out a form with your personal information and submitting it to us through our website, we collect the personal information that you provide to us. For example, if you register or sign up for an account with us, we collect your name, e-mail address, and password. If you place an order with us, we collect the personally identifiable information that you provide to us such as your shipping, billing, and payment information. 

From time-to-time Vistaprint may give you the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on our website. If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information.

From time-to-time Vistaprint may give you the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on our Website. If you participate, we will request certain Personal Information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose the requested information. _Information About Your Transactions With Us:_ In addition, we collect your order information and purchase and payment history.Cookies and Similar Files:Our Website uses “cookies” and files that are similar to cookies. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers created by your browser at our request and stored in an approved and standardized place on your computer. By transferring these cookies, Vistaprint assigns you a unique customer code and record locater. Information about your activity on our Website can then be included in your customer record, which is stored within the Vistaprint firewall. When you visit or return to our Website, we read the cookie to identify you as one of our customers and help recall orders or preferences you have selected. The cookie also enables us to recall your past activities, post your account data, and tailor site elements and special offers to you. No Personal Information about you is stored on the cookie.Most Web browsers accept cookies by default, but allow users to reject cookies by changing the browser preferences. If you have set up your browser to reject cookies, some aspects of our Website, including our Shopping Cart, will not work properly.If you have Macromedia Flash installed on your computer, we will also use a file called a Flash Object to store your unique customer code and record locater on your computer. Unless deactivated by you, the Flash Object provides us with a backup method for recognising you in the event that we are unable to identify your cookies.This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies and similar files by Vistaprint only and does not cover the use of cookies and similar files by any third party advertisers or websites linked to the Website.We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our behalf. These companies may use a cookie or an action tag, also known as a Web Beacon or a 1 pixel .gif file, to track your response to their advertisement and to measure the effectiveness of their advertising or to award incentives or points to their members who respond to their advertisements. Vistaprint has no access to or control over cookies or action tags used by these third party companies. Vistaprint does not receive any personally identifiable information collected by these advertisers using action tags or cookies nor does Vistaprint share any of your personally identifiable information such as your name, telephone number or address with these companies except in accordance with this Vistaprint Privacy Policy. Members of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) permit you to limit targeted advertising from them by using an opt-out tool available on the NAI website at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/consumer/opt_out.asp>.Use and Disclosure of Information:We use the information that we collect about you to maintain, improve, and administer our website, operate our business, provide products and services that you request, administer your account, inform you about products and services that might be of interest to you, and personalise your online experience.In order to carry out certain business functions, such as order fulfillment, e-mail delivery, or marketing, we sometimes hire other companies to perform services on our behalf. We may disclose personally identifiable information that we collect about you to these companies to enable them to perform these services, but they are required to safeguard the data and are not authorised to use it for any other purpose than completing their contractual requirements to Vistaprint. For example, as a part of the normal process of completing your purchase, Vistaprint may provide your personal data to a third party payment processor, such as Bibit B.V., depending on your chosen method of payment. Please be aware that, because of the limitations of the systems used by some financial institutions, the statement you receive from your credit card or financial institution may show the name of a third party payment processor, such as Bibit B.V., instead of or in addition to the Vistaprint name. In addition, we may share the information we collect with other companies with whom we have joint marketing arrangements.If you check the applicable box on registration or in updating your account, VistaPrint may also share personally identifiable information about you such as your name, telephone number, e-mail address, and/or mailing address with carefully selected third-party organisations such as retailers or direct marketers to enable those organizations to inform you about products or services that might be of interest to you. If you do not wish to have your information shared with these organisations, simply do not check the applicable box on the registration form or on the “Account Update” page on our website.   
We may also disclose information we collect about you in other circumstances as required or permitted by law. For example, VistaPrint reserves the right to disclose personally identifiable information, including account information, when we believe such disclosure is appropriate to cooperate with an investigation of activities claimed to be unlawful, to enforce our [Terms  
of Use](http://www.vistaprint.com/customer-care/terms-of-use.aspx?), or to protect the rights or property of VistaPrint or others. In addition, it is possible that in the future another company may acquire VistaPrint or its assets. It is also possible that VistaPrint may partner with or purchase another company to continue to do business as a combined entity. In the event that this occurs, it is possible that our customer information may be transferred to the new business entity as one of VistaPrint’s assets. In such an event, we will update this policy to reflect any change in ownership or control of your personal information.We may also disclose information, including Personal Information, we collect about you in other circumstances as required or permitted by law. For example, VistaPrint reserves the right to disclose Personal Information, including account information, when we believe such disclosure is appropriate to cooperate with an investigation of activities claimed to be unlawful, to enforce our [Terms of Use](http://www.vistaprint.com/customer-care/terms-of-use.aspx), or to protect the rights or property of VistaPrint or others. In addition, it is possible that in the future another company may acquire VistaPrint or its assets. It is also possible that VistaPrint may partner with or purchase another company to continue to do business as a combined entity. In the event that this occurs, it is possible that our customer information, including your Personal Information, may be transferred to the new business entity as one of VistaPrint’s assets. In such an event, we will update this policy to reflect any change in ownership or control of your Personal Information.Links To Third Party Products and ServicesWhile you are visiting or using the Vistaprint website, you may be presented with an opportunity to purchase third party products or services. These products and services are offered and supplied by independent companies not owned or operated by Vistaprint. If you click on one of the presented offers, you will be redirected to the site of the third party, and any information you provide in response to the offer will be collected and used by the third party and **_not_** by Vistaprint. Information you provide to the third party and any dealings you have with the third party will be governed by the privacy and other policies of that third party.Your Choices:We offer you a variety of choices with respect to how we use and share your personal information. _Sharing Information With Others._ We will not share your personally identifiable information, such as your e-mail address or name, with unaffiliated organizations for them to use to inform you about their or other companies’ products and services unless you consent to this sharing on registration or in updating your account preferences. You may opt in by checking the appropriate box during registration or, following registration, by logging into “My Account,” selecting “Account Update,” and checking the applicable box. You may also opt-in by sending a written request to the address below. If you send a written request, please be sure to include your exact name, mailing address and telephone number(s) and a statement that you would like us to share your personal information with other organizations that may have special offers, products or services that may be of interest to you. Even if you do not opt in to this sharing, we may still share personally identifiable information about you with other companies as permitted or required by law. _Communications from Vistaprint._ If you do not want to receive e-mails from Vistaprint about products and services that may be of interest to you, simply indicate this preference by removing the applicable check mark during registration. If you wish to change your preference after you have registered, you can do so by logging into “My Account,” selecting “Account Update, and updating your preference. You may also request to be added to our Do-Not-E-Mail list, Do-Not-Call list, and/or our Do-Not-Mail list by writing to the address below and indicating your preferences. Please be sure to provide your exact name, e-mail address, mailing address and telephone number(s) and the list or lists you would like to be included on (Do-Not-E-mail, Do-Not-Call, and/or Do-Not-Mail). Even if you choose to be placed on one of these lists, we may still communicate with you using any of these methods regarding your use of our website, your orders or your account. _Deactivation of Your Account._ You may also request deactivation of your VistaPrint account by contacting Customer Care at http://www.vistaprint.co.uk/customer-care/contact-us.aspx or by writing to the address below and requesting account deactivation. Please note that some information may remain in our archived records after your account has been deactivated. _Vistaprint Address for Written Requests._ If you choose to indicate your preferences by mail, please be sure to include your exact name, mailing address, telephone number and specific preferences and send your written requests to the following address 

Vistaprint Limited  
c/o Vistaprint USA Incorporated  
Customer Care  
95 Hayden Avenue  
Lexington MA 02421  
USA

How to manage your account:If you wish to change your name, e-mail address, password, communication and/or opt-in preferences after you have registered, you can access your account by logging into My Account and selecting Account Update. You may also request these changes by contacting customer care at http://www.vistaprint.co.uk/customer-care/contact-us.aspx or calling Customer Care at 0800 028 8251 or writing to: 

VistaPrint Limited  
c/o VistaPrint USA Incorporated  
Customer Care  
95 Hayden Avenue  
Lexington MA 02421  
USA

Website Security:We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards designed to help us protect your nonpublic personal information. For example, we use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology to encrypt your credit card information when you purchase products through our website. When you establish an account at Vistaprint, you choose a password to help protect your account information. A password is only as strong as you make it: you should select a unique password and keep it safe. You may change the password as often as you wish by going to “My Account” and selecting "Account Update."Vistaprint authorizes only those persons who need to know personal information to administer your account, to provide or inform you about products and services, or to maintain, improve or administer our website to access your personal information.With respect to certain website hosting and other products and services provided to you, we may obtain access to data about your end users or customers. We generally process and use such end user and customer data on your behalf and under your instructions in accordance with our role as a mere processor of any such information on your behalf.Changes to this Privacy Policy:This Privacy Policy was last modified on **_March 19, 2008_**. Vistaprint may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time by posting a revised Privacy Policy on our Website. We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently.Problems Signing InBack To TopOur sign-in process is designed to help protect your privacy. If you have trouble signing in to our website, please ensure that you are using your registered e-mail address and/or correct password. If you are using your registered e-mail address and correct password, and you continue to have trouble signing in to our site, please contact Customer Care.Order ConfirmationBack To TopVistaprint sends an e-mail notice confirming acceptance of each order you place to the e-mail address you provided to us when signing up for a Vistaprint account. If you receive a confirmation for an order you did not place, please e-mail us immediately at Customer Care.
